Go Mr. Balachandran uh you know retail
growth uh on the retail health side uh
what's the sustainability of that uh the
growth has been strong for you can it
sustain on a high base
>> yeah that's so that's a that's a good uh
question to begin with uh but before I
kind of respond to that just wanted to
kind of make sure that because we have
started on uh a new year so therefore to
that extent happy new year to all of you
and uh your viewers as as well. Uh but
now coming back to your point on how are
we seeing retail. So the way we see
retail for us spans across a couple of
key lines which is both motor and uh
health and let me take the health piece
first. Now retail health for ICO Lombard
has been an area of uh opportunity that
we had kind of been doing for the last
uh several quarters and in that
direction is where we have been we have
kind of invested a lot on uh building
our distribution uh that cuts across
multiple channels and equally I think we
have been kind of launching uh products
which are in the interest of uh
customers. Um now to specifically in the
context of how that has played out I
think in general historically for IC
Lumbard retail health our market share
used to be around 3%. The good news is I
think if you look at for quarter four
quarter 3 uh the market share as we
speak stands at about 4 and a half uh%.
And on a 9 month basis the market share
increase moved from 3.2 to 4%. So hence
I think that's done very well in terms
of incremental market share uh in line
with uh what we have been expecting and
in terms of growth I think what we are
very excited with is also some of the uh
governmental reforms that has happened
in the last quarter and which is kind of
uh significantly created a positive
growth for quarter 3 at almost about
86%. uh so very very excited in the way
how the growth momentum is play playing
out for ISIS Lumbard in the context of
retail health
right uh Mr. Mr. Balishand also wanted
to discuss uh the mo motor market share
as well. Are you seeing any signs of
recovery coming coming in and do you
think it's going to get better going
forward from here?
>> Again that's a that's a great point
which is what I was kind of referring to
in my earlier response. Uh until half
year of this year I think the gap
between the industry growth numbers and
ISO growth numbers has been at least
almost more than 500 basis points. uh
but if you were to see this gap uh for
quarter three has significantly got
reduced to almost uh about about a
percentage or thereabout. So clearly I
think the gap has significantly got
narrowed and more importantly within the
quarter 3 for the month of December
industry growth numbers in motor was
roughly about 12.4%.
ISIS Lombard's growth was almost about
16.1%. So we have actually kind of
outperformed the market when it comes to
motor uh uh in the month of December and
that is exactly what I spoke about is
something that we are quite excited with
how the rebound has started to kind of
play out and this is contributed by two
factors. One as I said some of the
governmental reforms in terms of uh
clearly uh bringing out GST reforms so
that has created demand for new vehicle
sales uh which has been a growth factor
for us. For example, in quarter three,
new vehicle or rather new growth was
almost about 12.4%.
And equally for ISIS Lumbard, we
continue to kind of look for retaining
our customers. So there again, I think
what we have seen is an increased
retentions of our customers. So both of
this have kind of aided growth in water.
>> Okay. Uh let let me talk uh Mr. Balachan
about CV growth as well because within
you you've given us good color on auto
but CV growth has has picked up so how
are the numbers shaping up for you give
us a sense of that
>> yeah so which is which is the point that
I made I think uh the good news is uh
the consumer demand is playing through
all the segments whether it's private
car two-heer or commercial vehicles and
even for the matter of fact the growth
is also much more broad-based as in to
say that it is not just happening only
in metro cities. The growth in motor is
kind of visible across tire 2 and tire
three cities as well. To your point on
commercial vehicles, I think within that
I think if I were to kind of look at uh
tractors as a category, I think that's
done phenomenally well. I think uh we
have been able to deliver growth in
excess of almost more than 30% plus. Uh
so that's a segment which we have been
very very actively looking at CV as a
category. But in so far as the mix of
private car, two-wheeler and commercial
vehicles for IC lumbards, that's
something that will keep changing and
that is a nimble footed that we'll have
to exhibit whenever we are kind of
writing businesses whether it is private
carheer or commercial vehicles,
>> right? But what about the combined ratio
because uh that still is elevated and
what trend should one expect going
forward?
Yeah. So that's a good question and let
me put this in context. Uh which is what
we have called out even in our earnings
transcript. Uh as you would recolct
effective October last year, I'm talking
about financial year 2425. There was a
change in the way accounting
prescriptions were laid down for
recognizing long-term policies. Now
obviously that tends to have an effect
in so far as uh the outcomes on the
combined is concerned uh between
quarters. uh but uh so rather a better
way to look at is the numbers on an end
basis which is to kind of uh so that the
numbers are consistently kind of viewed
if you view it in that context for
quarter 3 our combined ratio on an N
basis in previous year quarter 3 that
number was about 102.3
in quarter 3 of the current year on an N
basis the combined ratio actually has
kind of been better at about 102.2%.
to your specific point on 104.5%.
That's a number that's on a 1 byN basis
and as we have also laid down in our in
our disclosures, it does have an impact
of again a very good reforms that the
government has done in terms of
enhancing social security measures for
generally the employee/worker community
as a whole. Now that has had an impact
of almost about 100 basis point on the
combined for quarter 3. So what you see
as a combined of 104.5
has a one-time impact of almost about 55
crores that we have provided for
consequent to the implementation of the
new wage code and if you were to kind of
take that as one of impact which has
which is there in quarter 3 the reported
combined would have looked at 103.5
uh so that's something that one should
be mindful of but more importantly as we
keep saying I think one should always
keep looking at numbers more on a
year-to-ate basis and one of the other
things that we had spoken about also in
the earlier calls is to make sure that
IC lumbard is able to deliver a
sustained ROE in the range of 18 to 20%.
And as you would have seen on the 9
month basis our reported ROE was in that
range of uh 18 to 20% and that's
something that we believe we should
continue to sustain.
>> And what is the impact of the labor code
on profitability? What should
profitability be if one were to exclude
the labor code impact?
As I said the we welcome the new uh wage
code reforms that has been kind of put
into existence and the point that I made
55 crores is more a one-off impact which
is primarily resulting from an actual
valuation of our past service cost.
Equally there is an amount that we have
disclosed which is an amount of about 17
crores that is something that will get
amotized over the next three years. Uh
so those are the two impacts at this
point of time basis whatever guidelines/
rules that has been issued in the future
if at all there are any more guidelines
or rules that gets issued we will
obviously evaluate at that point of time
but currently 55 crores is a one-off
impact which has been fully absorbed in
the quarter 3 and 9 month numbers for
robot and the unotized cost of 17 crores
in accordance with the accounting
prescription will get amotized over the
next uh 3 years
>> right interesting to hear that Mr.